wmfamericas.com 2018-01-29

# Privacy Policy | WMF Americas

The privacy policy set out below (hereinafter the  **“Privacy Policy”**  or the  **“Policy”** ), explains the way in which the personal data collected on wmfamericas.com (hereinafter the  **“Website”** ) by Groupe SEB USA and SEB International Services (SIS), (together “We”, “Our”) each acting as a data controller, is used and where applicable, disclosed to third parties, the measures taken to ensure their confidentiality and security, as well as your choices with respect to the collection and use of your personal data.

The Policy does not apply to information We collect offline. Your use of this Website signifies your consent to Our Privacy Policy.

Information Collected and Purposes of Collection

When you access and use the Website you may provide certain personal data relating to you, i.e. information that may allow identifying you directly or indirectly.

Information that may be collected by Groupe SEB USA when you create an account, request a catalogue or information about our products and services, take part in a game or a quiz, or by SIS when you make a purchase, may include: your first name and last name, address, phone number, e-mail address, user ID and password associated to your user account, your gender, your date of birth, your interests and preferences. 

Some of the information that you may be asked to provide on the Website is mandatory and will be marked as such; some is optional. If you choose not to provide information which is mandatory, you may not be able to access certain parts of the Web Site or we may not be able to respond to requests. 

Moreover, in order to improve the operation of the Website and adapt it to your requests, information such as your IP address, your browser type, your operating system, the language used, the pages of the Website that you viewed and the order in which you viewed them, the date and duration of your visit, as well as other information that is collected via the use of cookies, may be collected. For more details about the cookies we use, please see our paragraph related to  **Cookies**.

How is your data used?

When you create an account on the Website, your personal data is processed by Groupe SEB USA which may use it for the following purposes:  
\- to enable the creation of your user account and respond to your searches and or requests for information concerning the goods or services sold by Groupe SEB USA;   
\- in order to send you promotional and marketing offers that might be of interest to you, in accordance with your choices in this regard;  
\- in order to provide you with personalised content and offers on the Website;   
\- in connection with your participation to a game or a quiz, or in any other events available on the Website.   
When you make a purchase on the Website, your personal data will be processed by SIS for managing your order and the delivery.

Security

We have implemented reasonable, technical, administrative and physical safeguards to protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of your personal information. However, We cannot make any guarantees to you with respect to the security of information you provide to Us. You agree that We will have no liability for the disclosure of any information obtained due to errors in transmission or the unauthorized acts of third parties. If you have reason to believe that your use of the Website is no longer secure, please contact us as detailed below.  
In order to help us protect your data, we recommend that you avoid using an identifier or a password that are too obvious, and regularly change your password and ensure that you never disclose it to anyone.

Choices

Groupe SEB USA may use your personal information to contact you concerning changes to our Website, new products/services and other information relating to Groupe SEB USA’s business. In the event that you do not wish to receive marketing emails from us, please unsubscribe at any time by simply following the unsubscribe instructions in such emails. Please note that even if you opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us, we may still need to send you service-related communications.   
You may also access and update certain personal information by contacting us as detailed below. We will try to comply with your requests as soon as reasonably practicable.  
We may need to retain and use certain personal information for recordkeeping purposes, to complete any prior request, as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, or for other purposes as required or permitted by applicable law. 

Third Party Sharing and Use of Information

 We do not share your personal information collected on this Website with third parties, except in the following instances:

**• Third Party Vendors:**  From time to time, We may engage third party vendors to perform, on its behalf, functions such as sending postal mail and responding to e-mails, Website evaluation, analyzing data and providing customer service and support. These approved third parties will only have access to information to the extent necessary and will not be authorized to use any personal information for any purpose other than providing such services We have contracted for. In addition, We require that these third party vendors maintain the confidentiality of such information.

**• Special Cases:**  We may also disclose personal information to third parties as required or permitted by local law, in order to comply with applicable law, subpoena or similar legal request, to enforce our Terms of Use, or to protect the rights, property or safety of the Website and the safety of our users. 

**• Business Transfers:**  In the event that all or a portion of the assets relating to the Website are transferred or sold to another entity, please note that personal information may be transferred to the acquiring entity without notice to you with the stipulation that such information continue to be treated in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy.

We may also share aggregate and/or non-individual statistical information (e.g. non-personally identifiable information) about you with third parties, such as advertising and marketing affiliates. 

Third party websites

The Website may contain links to websites operated by third parties which are not governed by this Privacy Policy and whose practices in terms of collection and use of personal data are likely to be different from those of the Website. As Groupe SEB USA and SIS do not own or operate such websites, they hereby disclaim liability for the way in which these third party web sites may collect and use your personal data. We recommend that you read carefully the privacy policies of these third party web sites.

Use of your personal data from accounts created on another web site or service of the T-fal brand

If you have created a user account on another web site or service of the T-fal brand, we will use your personal data from this account to complete the data of your user account on the Website, in order to facilitate your registration on the Website and enable you to avoid having to re-enter in information that you may have already provided. If you do not wish your data from other user accounts created on another web site or service of the T-fal brand to be used in this way, please contact the customer service by writing to the address mentioned in the last section below.

Cookies and Targeted Advertising

Cookies are small pieces of information that most websites store on your computer's hard drive when you visit them, along with similar technologies such as pixel tags, local shared objects and web beacons that are present on the websites you may visit (collectively, "Cookies"). We use Cookies to improve and maintain the Website and to give you opportunities to purchase products on our Website and on other unaffiliated websites you may visit.  We also allow third parties to use Cookies on our Website to provide you with a more personalized experience on the internet. As you may know, most web browsers' settings allow you to deny or accept certain Cookies.  However, in the event that you do not accept certain Cookies from this Website, please note that you may not be able to access certain pages contained therein or receive certain services on the Website.

To learn more about Cookies in connection with targeted advertising and the choices you have, please visit [Digital Advertising Alliance ](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)or the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).  Please note that even if you opt-out of such Cookies, you may continue to receive advertisements, they just will not be tailored to your interests.  

Under California law, we are also required to let you know how we respond to browsers' "Do Not Track signals."  At this time, we do not honor Do Not Track requests.

Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998

Groupe SEB USA and SIS are committed to complying fully with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998. We do not target our Website to users who are under 13, and in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, if we have actual knowledge of children under age 13 using the Website, there personal information will be deleted from our systems.

Updates to the Privacy Policy

Should the Privacy Policy be modified, the new Privacy Policy will be displayed on this Website. We recommend that you check it regularly to learn of any changes that we may bring to it.

Your rights in relation to the processing of your personal data

In accordance with applicable data protection and privacy laws, you may access, correct, delete and/or object to the processing of your personal data upon legitimate grounds and exercise any other rights to which you are entitled to under applicable laws with respect to the processing of personal data. In order to do so please contact the customer service by writing to the address mentioned in the last section below.

Contact Information

Questions about this Privacy Policy may be directed to [Customer Service ](http://www.t-falusa.com/consumer-services/contact-us-m)or a written communication to:   
WMF Consumer Service  
Attn. Webmaster – Privacy   
2199 Eden Road   
Millville, NJ 08332 

Please note that any questions about our products/services directed to this address will not be replied to.
